# SATYA NARAYAN BOSE

# **UI/UX Designer**

Email: satyabose.uiux@gmail.com

Phone: +1 848-219-9521
Portfolio: SATYABOSE.COM

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/satyabose

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMERY**

10 years of IT experience in Web UI Design, Interaction design & Visual design, Sketching, Wire framing Dashboards Designs with low and hi-fidelity design with the designing tools like Sketch, Axure RP, Adobe Xd cc, Invision, Balsamiq, Photoshop, illustrator and making extensive rapid and dynamic prototype, mock-up using HTML5/CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, D3 Animations, JavaScript with JavaScript framework JQuery UI experience in the software development life cycle. Strong debugging and problem-solving skills with excellent understanding of Responsive Designing with browser compatibility techniques and tools.

#### **TECHNOLOGY**

Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, illustrator) CorelDraw, In Design, Balsamiq, Adobe XD cc, Axure RP, Sketch, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, iQuery, Bootstrap, JavaScript.

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Applications (MCA) – From Punjab Technical University - 2005 – 2008.

Bachelor's Degree - B.Com (Graduation) from Utkal University - 2000 - 2005

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Sr. UI/UX DESIGNER

# **CVS HEALTH**

<sup>™</sup>Aug. 2017 - Currently | • Monroeville, PA

Responsible for user experience and interface design for Collection, a web and mobile application. Responsibilities included wire framing, work flow and documentation for rapid prototyping and designing in browser.

### Roles:

- Collecting requirements from Business team template and creating initial sketching, Wireframes Designs,
   Prototyping, Dashboards Design using Axure RP and creating interactive prototypes using Adobe XD CC and visual lyout design for desktop web using designing tools Photoshop/illustrator.
- Creation of screens for desktop and mobile application with Angular PrimeNG component and creation of UI/UX design with W3C Web Accessibility style guide design using HTML/CSS3.
- Components, design patterns, typography, Custom icon library creation and other valuable resources to help with the consistent representation of project brand visual enhancement and user experience.
- Preparing UI/UX documenting, maintaining and user training, experience on AGILE design methodologies for the sprint planning.
- Working on **mobile responsive** iPhone & android devices integration for browser compatibility and coordinating with the development team.
- Work extensively with the backend developer on different JS frameworks HTML5 and CSS3 (SASS) to resolve UI issues.
- Creation of custom icon using **CSS FONT** like icommon, font awesome.

# Sr. UI/UX DESIGNER

# **VERISK ANALYTICS**

<sup>™</sup>May 2015 – July 2017 | • Jersey City, NJ

Responsible for user experience and interface design for Collection, a web and mobile application. Responsibilities included wire framing, work flow and documentation for rapid prototyping and designing in browser.

## Roles:

- Collecting requirements from Business team template and creating initial sketching, **Wireframes** Designs, **Navigation** using **Adobe Xd cc** and visual design for desktop web using **Photoshop/illustrator**.
- Creation of screens for desktop and mobile application with Google **Material design guidelines** and creation of UI/UX Accessibility design **style guide** with W3C standard design using **HTML/CSS**.
- Components, design patterns, typography, Custom icon library creation and other valuable resources to help with the consistent representation of project brand visual enhancement and user experience.

- Preparing UI/UX documenting, maintaining and user training, experience on **AGILE** design methodologies for the every sprint planning.
- Working on **mobile responsive** iPhone & android devices integration and browser compatibility and coordinating with the development team.
- Develop the whole **SASS** pre-processor for CSS structure to support massive branding need.
- Work extensively with the backend developer on different JS frameworks HTML5 and CSS3 (SASS) to resolve UI issues.
- Creating D3 animations and creation of new product custom icons using CSS FONT.

## **UI/UX DESIGNER**

# **PROLIFICS**

Provided creative direction for the **Prolifics's** products team and onsite Clients for responsibilities of designers, UX/UI and visual design collecting requirements from Business Stake Holders and develop dynamic wireframes and visual design for desktop web and mobile applications in a store environment. Performed UI, functionality, integration, regression and acceptance testing for client server, web and host based applications.

#### Roles:

- Collecting requirements from Business team, Stake holder, Product owners and creating initial sketch using
  Sketch and develop dynamic Wireframes and visual design for desktop web and mobile applications in a
  store environment. Performed UI, functionality, integration, web and host based applications.
- Work closely with Product Owner and Business Team from designing phase on every level. Develop various ideas in order to enhance UI and UX experience.
- Creation of dashboards and layouts screens for desktop and mobile application with Google Material design guidelines and creation of UI/UX design style guide with Web Accessibility Usability testing, Interaction design using Adobe Photoshop /illustrator.
- Components, design patterns, **typography**, **iconography** and other valuable resources to help with the consistent representation of project brand visual enhancement and user experience.
- Preparing UI/UX documenting, maintaining and user training, experience on AGILE and SCRUM design methodologies for the every sprint planning.
  - Working on mobile responsive iPhone & android devices integration and browser compatibility and coordinating with the development team.
- Develop the whole SASS, LESS pre-processor for CSS structure to support massive branding need.
- Work extensively with the backend developer on different JS frameworks **HTML5** and **CSS3** (SASS) to resolve UI issues.

# **UI DESIGNER LEAD**

# vSplash Techlabs Pvt. Ltd.

<sup>™</sup>Jan 2008 - Feb 2011 | ♥ INDIA

Responsible for user experience and interface design for Collection, a web and mobile application. Responsibilities included wire framing, work flow and documentation as well as front end development for rapid prototyping and designing in browser.

### Roles:

- Design information architecture, information design, visual design, Sketching, wireframes, and interactive
  prototypes to support the complete cohesive user experience. Work extensively on Bootstrap, HTML5,
  CSS3, Media queries for responsiveness.
- Layout designing of the websites and Banners using flash and jQuery library.
- Designed low and high fidelity wireframes using Axure RP, Photoshop and prototypes.
- Enhance the old mock-up of the intranet site based on the new Wireframes with W3C Standard.
- Work with Data Structures, Algorithms, and Complexity Analysis.
- Work with extensive usage of JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery/AJAX.
- Work on consolidating multiple legacy system with jQuery UI. Develop UI components for different modules using High Charts, and Data Tables.
- Make sure product has the ability to support multiple languages.
- Responsible for Quality Assurance of Web Usability and Accessibility

## **WORK URLS**

http://rta.ae http://www.lexus.ae http://www.toyota.ae http://rakbankdirect.ae

## **ONSITE CLIENT PROJECTS**

Government of Dubai | UAE, Rakbank Dubai | UAE, Al-Futtaim of Dubai | UAE, Horizon BCBS | NJ, Verisk Analytics | NJ, CVS Health | PA